FRANKLIN OKECH DATA ANALYST

Summary

An Information Technology Expert with a strong background in software development and data analytics with 4+ years of documented accomplishments in both Software development and data analysis across numerous industries and technology platforms. A change agent and a strategist who not only think but does the execution and has been successful in overhauling systems at various companies aimed at achieving desired outcomes and increase operational efficiencies by relying on data to make decisions

Employment

Kidogo Early Years

Nairobi Feb. 2022 to Current

Data Systems Analyst

- Collaborated with 2 data engineers and 1 project manager to develop a data warehouse to improve Kidogo M&E systems to improve the quality of insights hence timely decisions.
- Developed a visually impactful dashboard in Power BI to identify key metrics and transform raw data into meaningful, actionable insight for the field teams.
- Contributed to the increase in member retention rates by about 25% through predictive analysis throughout the member journey.

Co-op Bank

Kenva

Data Engineer

Jan. 2022 to Feb. 2022

- Collaborated with a team of 6 data engineers to set up a data pipeline for a new co-op bank data warehouse platform
- Collaborated with 4 BI developers to align the bank's new data needs with stakeholders
- Contributed to increase in the availability of core customer data in the data warehouse to about 90% which reduce the time for insight generations and actions

The Room Data and Research Analyst

Remote June 2021 to Nov. 2021

- Collaborated with 1 data analyst Intern and 1 project lead to improve jobs curation effort in the room for better data-driven decisions.
- Developed a visually impactful dashboard in Google data studio to identify key jobs that align with talent in The Room which saved time and effort for the pathfinding team.
- Contributed to the increase in The Room talent hires by about 20% by providing tailored jobs that suit individual talent needs.

Komaza Forestry Limited Data Ops Assistant

Kilifi Feb. 2019 to June 2021

- In collaboration with 1 data analyst and 1 project manager, developed the data warehouse for the harvest department aimed at data available for informed decision-making for the operations team.
- Developed harvest dashboard using Google data studio that tracked key metrics and KPIs which ensured operational and strategic decisions were made in a data-driven and timely manner.
- Contributed to the timber harvesting costs from \$100/cbm to \$40/cbm through data-driven operational planning that aimed at the efficiency and effectiveness of the harvest team

ICT Authority

Nairobi

ICTA Standards Intern

May 2018 to Jan. 2019

- Designed an E-readiness survey tool that was used to assess and rank government parastatals and ministries E-readiness
- Successfully conducted system audit for over 5 government Ministries, Corporations, and Agencies including the NHIF, KEPHIS, and NEW KCC
- Involved in the design and deployment of the ICTA accreditation system as a developer
- Involved in the background check for over 200 ICT firms for their ICT accreditation compliance

Contact

- franklinokech@gmail.com
- franklinokech github io
- **4** +254700520718
- ♥ Kahawa Wendani. Nairobi
- f franklinokech
- **y** franklinokech
- in franklinokech
- franklinokech

Education

Maseno University Sept. 2013 to Dec. 2017

Bsc. Information Technology 2017 Second Class Upper Division, Founding Member Maseno Mozilla Firefox Academy

Wiobiero Secondary Feb. 2009 to Nov. 2012

KCSE Mean Grade A-(77), Librarian for 2 Academic Years

Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Python

SQL

Javascript

Bash

R

VISUALIZATION

Jupyter Notebooks

Google Data Studio

Excel Charts

Google Sheets Charts

Power BI

DBMS/STORAGE

Postgres

MvSOL

SQL Server

Big Query

Oracle

OTHER TOOLS

Git

QGIS

Survey CTO

Kobocollect

SOFT SKILLS

Verbal Communication Written Communication

Presentation

Leadership